Hello everyone. Welcome back to our post-grid SQL T2LC.
So, today we are going to explore for how to drop table in the post-grid SQL database using
for the drop table statement, okay.
So, first of all, I can simply explain for the post-grid SQL drop table and in this statement
for the post-grid SQL uses to remove one or more tables from the database, okay.
So, it's operation in database management for allowing us to delete unnecessary table
and free up resource, okay.
So, here, first of all, dropping the single table, okay.
So, now, let's start with the simple example of dropping a single table from the database,
okay.
So, now here, I can just put it for the drop table statement.
So, first of all, here I am going to type this is the drop table.
And here I can use for the data for the database name and here I can choose for the one
more table already created and now I can choose for the active table, okay.
So, now, first of all here, I can use the new table and select and multiple sign and from
here the active.
So, this is the active table, okay.
So, now here, I can select and execute and you can see here the active table information,
okay.
So, I hope you understand it and now just remove all active table, okay.
So, now just go here and now here I can create this for the active table and here I have
already prepared the active table for the statement and this statement will follow the table's
name, the active and this will delete for the active table from the database, okay.
So, now just select and execute, you can see here, this is the commonly successful
and operation is successful and of course we will return a confirmation message, okay.
So, now I can verify and I can select this execute using the execute.
So, now the table is already created, okay.
So, now you can try for the multiple table is dropping.
So, now for the possible.
So, now here we can go in for the statement and first of all here I am going to remove
all the active tables and here I can remove for the another table suppose.
I can choose for the table so first I can choose for the user.
So, here I can define the user table and also here I can choose for the temperature, okay.
So, the temp, pr, d, r, s, so the temperature table and here I have already picked two
tables first I can check here I can use the users and now just left and execute and you
can see this is the user table information, okay.
So, open the another new query and there I can just start this is select then start from
the temperature, okay.
So, here this is the temperature table is created, now we can select perfectly just type
this is the select, okay.
So, here I define this the select completely done and now execute and you can see here
this is select table all the information, okay.
So, you can see here perfectly define the list and now going forward and all can use for
the multiple table just drop.
So, here insert for the two table and first of all here use and second for the temperature
table for the database and now select and execute and it will perfectly work you can see
the operation is successful and post query query return the confirmation message, okay.
So, first I will check the inside table to verify so here I can create completely the stream
so just select an execute and you can see here I can invalid the name the 16A for because
delete the drop point table, okay.
So, next here the temperature so here I can just open select and execute and you can see
here perfectly drop the temperature table, okay.
So, here the decision is completely done and perfectly dropped the two tables so I hope
you perfectly understand and have an overview of the dropping table for the post query
SQL database with some practical example, okay.
So, I hope you perfectly find this tutorial helpful so stay tuned for more postware SQL
tips and tips, okay.
So, thank you for watching and happy coding, okay.